The trial that brought down Alcatraz.
Murder in the First is a crime, drama film directed by Marc Rocco.
A young, inexperienced public defender is assigned to defend an
inmate accused of committing murder while behind bars.
James Stamphill, played by Christian Slater.
Henri Young, played by Kevin Bacon.
Associate Milton Glenn, played by Gary Oldman.
Mary McCasslin, played by Embeth Davidtz.
Bill McNeill, played by William H. Macy.
Mr. Henkin, played by Stephen Tobolowsky.
Murder in the First is a 1995 American legal drama film, directed by Marc Rocco, written by Dan Gordon, and
starring Christian Slater, Kevin Bacon, Gary Oldman, Embeth Davidtz, Brad Dourif, William H.
Macy, and R.
It tells the alternate history of a petty criminal named Henri Young who is sent to Alcatraz Federal Penitentiary and later put on
trial for murder in the first degree as the lawyer representing him recounts Henri's life and when he represented Henri.
This film was described on the movie poster as
"the case that took down Alcatraz".
The film received a mixed critical response, although
Bacon's performance was praised by critics.
The film explores themes of prison, prisoner,
death row, alcatraz prison, lawyer.
The tone is emotional.